Brian Reed

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

As a software engineer I enjoy developing responsive customer focused applications to demonstrate my commitment, providing solutions for companies and customers. I am a Web Developer with a focus on React, Javascript, Node, Mongo and Express. I also have experience with styling using CSS and custom styled components using Material UI. I am also open to learning new languages, libraries and frameworks whichever enhances the customers experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer at 100devs, Remote, Los Angeles, CA

Sep 2020 — Present

- Creating MVP's for customers.
- Researching technology to implement for customer MVP's.
- · Working with teams on creating software.
- Collaboration and communication between engineers on projects. Continuously learning new skill sets and technologies to meet customer needs.

Recent Projects:

Social Again (Fullstack Web App) – A social networking application for software technology enthusiasts to be social again. It allows users to create a profile, upload a photo, share software tech stack, share contact information and share comments.

Built with: JavaScript, Node, EJS, Express, Mongoose, NoSQL / Mongo DB, CSS, HTML

Web Developer at Brian Reed Web Solutions | Portland, OR

Sep 2016 — Present

I create customer focused, user friendly, responsive websites for small and medium size businesses. Iterative improvement researching various NPM libraries and frameworks for customer focused websites. Using modern frameworks and Libraries such as React, Node, JavaScript, MongoDB.

Truck Driver | USA

Jan 2015 — Jan 2017

Driving to customers locations using Time Management Software to make sure customer time needs are met. Using software systems to inventory items for transport. Managing teams using relocation software to coordinate relocation. Driving a Semi-Truck to customer locations safely.

- Using electronic time management software.
- Using GPS software to navigate route.
- Using Inventory software to inventory product.
- Effective communication with moving coordinators.

Inventory Control Specialist at Walmart | Washington, USA

January 2014 — Jan 2015

Using inventory software for items in their perspective areas. Using inventory control system software to update quantity. Navigating inventory control systems using effective communication to address problems, and solve problems.

CONTACT

Phone:

1-971-864-3362

Email:

brian.reed.software

@outlook.com

Portfolio:

www.brian-reed.me

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/

brian-reed-software

Github:

github.com/brian-reed-software/

Twitter:

twitter.com/brian_software_

Sms:

brian-reed.mfs.gg/contact

SKILLS

JavaScript ES6

React

Node

MongoDB

GitHub

Axios

EJS

Express

Mongoose

Styled Components

Bootstrap

CSS

HTML

OOP

Web Accessibility

EDUCATION

Portland Community College

Computer Science

2022